A Guide to the Papers of James J. Kilpatrick
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of James J. Kilpatrick
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-b
The collection consists of ca. 35,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by James J. Kilpatrick on January 11, 1968.
Biographical/Historical Information
James J. Kilpatrick (November 1, 1920–August 15, 2010) was an American editorial columnist and grammarian who offered conservative views on subjects ranging from politics to the proper use of English.
At the Richmond News Leader, Mr. Kilpatrick wrote editorials that thundered support for "massive resistance" to race-mixing in public schools, an effort pushed by the political machine of U.S. Sen. Harry F. Byrd, Sr. that worked to shut down public schools rather than integrate them.
Mr. Kilpatrick rose to national prominence at the Richmond paper. In books, essays and editorials, he was known for clothing segregationist doctrine in the terms of constitutional argument. For example, he gave new life to the idea of interposition championed by antebellum Sen. John C. Calhoun of South Carolina, who argued that states could protect their citizens from the authority of the federal government. Many Southern states began to pass pro-segregation laws that adopted the interposition language promoted by Kilpatrick.
Kilpatrick began writing his syndicated political column, "A Conservative View," in 1964 and left the News Leader in 1966. His stature as a writer, lecturer and commentator on public-affairs shows led to his appearances on the "60 Minutes" segment "Point-Counterpoint" in the 1970s. On the program, Mr. Kilpatrick debated such policy issues as family planning and the Vietnam War against liberal authors Nicholas von Hoffman and later Shana Alexander. "Point-Counterpoint" was memorably parodied on "Saturday Night Live" with Dan Aykroyd and Jane Curtin in the roles. "Jane, you ignorant slut," became a national catchphrase uttered by Aykroyd's character. "Dan, you pompous ass," was Curtin's retort.
In addition to "A Conservative View," Mr. Kilpatrick wrote the syndicated columns "Covering the Courts," which focused on the U.S. Supreme Court, and "The Writer's Art," a column about language and what he considered its frequent misuse. Kilpatrick collaborated on a book, "A Political Bestiary" (1978), a satirical dictionary of government jargon, with cartoonist Jeff MacNelly.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence and the writings of James Jackson Kilpatrick while he was editor of the Richmond News Leader (1954-1966), ca. 35,000 items (69 Hollinger boxes, 29.5 linear feet), ca. 1925-1966 (bulk 1950-1966). It includes correspondence with his readers and prominent public figures, editorials, speeches and public appearances, and the books The Sovereign States (1957), The Lasting South (1957), The Smut Peddlers (1960), and The Southern Case for School Segregation (1962). The dominant theme of the collection is Federal infringement on State's Rights which includes segregation, interposition, and fluoridation. Other topics include payola, Richmond, Virginian's baseball team, the National Conference of Editorial Writers, and a debate with Martin Luther King, Jr. on the nation's future (see Box 62)
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: Series I: Correspondence (Boxes 1-57); Series II: Editorials and Editorial Materials (Boxes 58-62); Series III: Speeches and Public Appearances (Boxes 62-64); and, Series IV: Book Manuscripts and Reviews (Boxes 65-69
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence
  - 1954-1967 Correspondence: A - Ac (Box-folder 1:1)
    Leslie Aaron, Paul Aaron, Irving S. Abady, Congressman Watkins M. Abbitt, C.E. Abbott, Wilbur C. Abbott, Deryck Abel, Esther Abele, Janet C. Abele, Allen Abell, Jules Abels, Anita W. Abernathy, E. Morris Abernathy, Louis D. Abney, W. Vincent Abrahamson, Accounting of Public Funds, Clair F. Achenbach, D.G. Ackerly, R. Ackerman, John Acord, James M. Acosta-Church of St. James the Less, John Q. Acree
  - 1956-1967 Correspondence: Ad - Ak (Box-folder 1:2)
    E. Ross Adair, John H. Adair, Berkley M. Adams, C.A. Adams, Edward G. Adams, Eileen Adams, Harry K. Adams, Helen DeWitt Adams, J.H. Adams, Mr. and Mrs. Nye Adams, Philip R. Adams, T.D. Adams (Correspondent and Subject, Correspondence with editors of other newspapers), Taylor Adams, Theodore F. Adams, Lee J. Adamson, Mary Ann Adamson, Nathaniel E. Adamson Jr., Addresses, Andrew E. Adelson, J.H.O. Adendorff, Jerry G. Adkins, Afro-American Newspapers, Robert E. Agnes, Raymond B. Ahearn, Carsten Ahrens, Karl M. Aijian, A.M. Aiken, Robert H. Akerman-Florida Southern College, Milburn P. Akers
  - 1956-1967 Correspondence: Al - All (Box-folder 1:3)
    "The Alarmist", Spencer Albright, Alderman Library, Merle N. Alderman, Creed Alderson, Arthur Douglass Alexander III, Bevin Alexander, Holmes Alexander, Hugh F. Alexander, Sen. John Alexander, Margaret Alexander, O.O. Alexander, Robert H. Alexander, M.E. Alford, Allegiance-The Constitution Game, Allen- Scott Column, Clyde N. Allen, Elizabeth H. Allen, George E. Allen-Allen, Allen, Allen and Allen, Hugh Allen, Jeanne Allen, Leroy Allen, Mary L. Allen, Richard Allen, Richard C. Allen, Mrs. Robert F. Allen, Steve Allen, T.E. Allen-Southern Cotton Oil Division, Urban M. Allen, John G. Allerdice, Alliance for Progress, Allied Ambulance Service, C.W. Allison Jr., Mr. and Mrs. Robert B. Allport, Eugene Allright, F.J. Allston Jr.-General Electric
  - 1956-1965 Correspondence: Lt. Gen. Edward M. Almond (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 1950-1967 Correspondence: Almond - Am (Box-folder 1:5)
    J. Lindsay Almond, Josephine M. Almond, Charles A Alston Jr., Ivan Alten, Daniel B. Altera, Mrs. Martin B. Altman, Joyce Alty, Mrs. Ed C. Alumbaugh, Mrs. Lorenzo Alvary, Mary Alves, American Academy of Public Affairs, American Airlines, American Bar Association, American Bar Association Journal, American Broadcasting Company, American Challenge, American Civil Liberties Union, American Coalition of Patriotic Societies, American Good Government Societies, American Institute of Architecst-Virginia Chapter, American Medical Association, American Museum of Photography, American Press Institute, American Society of Newspaper Editors, American Tobacco Company, American Way Features, Americans for Constitutional Action, America's Future, E. Almer Ames Jr., William T. Amis, Clarence O. Amonette, J.D. Ambrose
  - 1956-1967 Corrrespondence: An-Anderson (Box-folder 1:6)
    Newton Ancarrow, Philip W. Ancell, A.L. Anderson, A. Scott Anderson, Alice Anderson, Bruce Anderson, E.M. Anderson, Edgar S. Anderson, George Anderson, Mrs. J.S. Anderson, Jean Anderson, Jack R. Anderson, Dr. James L. Anderson, John C. Anderson, Paul B. Anderson -Boyertown Publishing, Richard Anderson Jr., Richard D. Anderson, Richard N. Anderson Jr. Robert B. Anderson, Robert C. Anderson, Dr. Samuel A. Anderson, Thomas H. Anderson, Virginia S. Anderson, Walter B. Anderson, William H.W. Anderson-Tobacco Growers' Information Committee, William R. Anderson, Willis M. Anderson
  - 1953-1967 Correspondence: Anderton - Anthony (Box-folder 2:1)
    Roland Anderton, Aaaron L. Andrews, James K. Andrews, Mrs. Jay D. Andrews, Leo R. Andrews Jr., M. Carl Andrews, Robert M. Andrews, Mrs. Ramon W. Andrews, T. Coleman Andrews, John E. Anfin, Arman Angelo, Marcia D. Anneke, Dr. Walter T. Annon, Anonymous Student at Virginia Union University, Frank and C. Kessler Anthony-1776 Magazine, Charles Anthony
  - 1953-1966 Correspondence: Anty - Armstrong (Box-folder 2:2)
    Anty[?]-Seattle Skeet and Trap Club, Rose Api, Cleanliness Bureau, Charles H. Appel, Muriel M. Appel, Cornelius Apperson, Ellen V. Apperson, Application Letters, John Apsley-Pennsylvania Society of Newspaper Editors, Irene Arcaro, Dr. Vincent W. Archer-University of Virginia Hospital Radiology, Joseph Arcuri-publisher, Mary (Mrs. Jules) Arginteanu-League of Women Voters, The Arizona Republic, Mrs. J.W. Armentrout, Fontaine C. Armistead-Virginia Institute for Scientific Research, Susan Lee Armistead, A.L. Armstrong, Harold N. Armstrong, Louis L. Armstrong, Newton Armstrong (subject), O.K. Armstrong, Peggy Armstrong, Richard R. Armstrong, Robert H. Armstrong, Theodore R. Armstrong, William A. Armstrong
  - 1952-1966 Correspondence: Arnold - As (Box-folder 2:3)
    Bill Arnold-Information Officer-Virginia Department of Conservation and Economic Development, Fred W. Arnold, John W. Arnold, Remmie L. Arnold, Arnolda Ranch Country Club, M.S. Arnoni - The Minority of One, M.J. Arrighi-Commander-Federal Post 141 American Legion, C. Ralph Arthur-Ferrum Junior College, Godwin Arts, Lena Artz, Andrew J Asch Jr., M. Ethel Ash, Rev. F. Ash Jr., Howard H. M. D. Ashbury-Virginia Department of Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Richard Ashman, Harry S. Ashmore-Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Mrs. Mary Wells Ashworth, Mrs. George Ashworth, Col. George F. Ashworth, Richard B.M. Askew, Asphalt Institute, Francis H. Aspinwall, Assembly of the State, Associate Editor, Associated Press, Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, Virginia Withers Ast
  - 1955-1967 Correspondence: At-End "A" (Box-folder 2:4)
    Atheneum Society of America, Gary L. Atkins-Dartmouth Conservative Society, Anne Atkinson-Chamberlayne, Clinton H. Atkinson, M.G. Atkinson, Walter Atkinson, Atlantic Rural Exposition, J.W. Atmar Sr. -Atmar Distributing, Stella R. Attkisson, Judge William Hawley Atwell, Bernhard M. Auer- Time Magazine, A.E. Auger, Harriet V. Aunspaugh, James A. Austin, Mrs. Robert G. Austin, Mrs. H.L. Avans, C. Philip Avery Jr., Dr. Alfred Avins-National Labor Relations Board and Memphis State University, AVIS Rent-a- Car, Col. Harry M. Ayers- The Anniston Star, Jane Ayers-American Association for the Advancement of Science, Walter Ayers, B.D. Ayres, Drummond Ayres, John W. Ayres, Mrs. Willis E. Ayres
  - 1955-1967 Correspondence: B - Bak (Box-folder 2:5)
    K. Baarslag, Andrew Babb-Sigma Alpha Epsilon, Frederic Babcock - Chicago Tribune, G.N. Babcock, Helen Brewer Babcock, M. Catherine Babcock, James T. Baber - Cumberland County Industrial Development Corporation, Mrs. Myrtis J. Baber, Milton J. Babin, A.M. Bachman Jr., John L. Bachman, Mrs. Robert J. Bachman-United Daughters of the Confederacy, E.C. Backus, Elmore C. Bacon Jr., John Joseph Baecher, Tommy Baer, Ben H. Bagdikian, H.B. Bagby-Commercial and Pictorial Photography, Sterling Bagby-Virginia Library Association, D.H. Bagley, Phil J. Bagley -Vice-Mayor of Richmond, Bernadine Bailey, C. Fred Bailey, Mrs. Edward Bailey, J.L. Bailey, Lt. Larry W. Bailey-USNR Seal Team 2 USNAB, Lillian Bailey, Rita J. Bailey, Adolphus E. Baird, Mrs. G. Lemando Baird, Anne Baker Incident, Barry Baker, C. Alden Baken, David A. Baker, E. Ballard Baker-Richmond-First Club, E. Monroe Baker, Mrs. George S. Baker Jr. (with letter written from Governor Albertis S. Harrison Jr.), Richard Baker, Thomas G. Baker - The Emporium Department Store, William A. Baker, W.R. Baker, Rev. Cornelius Nicholas Bakker-Oakton Community Church
  - 1956-1965 Correspondence - Bal (Box-folder 2:6)
    Stanley R. Balderson, Edward Baldic, Anne S. Baldwin, Louis M. Balfour, Irene M. Bality, Elizabeth H. Ball, Jay Ball, Dr. John Ball -Miami University of Ohio, John W. Ball, Robert T. Ball, Wanda Ball, Prof. William B. Ball-Villanova University, Anne Ballard, Louis W. Ballou, Mrs. Quintin Ballou, Emily Balls
  - 1956-1967 Correspondence: Bam - Bark (Box-folder 3:1)
    Joseph S. Bambacus-United States Attorney, Mrs. Povl Bang-Jensen, W.M. Banick Jr.-American Cyanamid Company. James Banks RD USNTC Great Lakes, J.H. Baptist-Boydton Manufacturing Company, Stella K. Barbee, Frank D. Barber, Herman Humphrey Barbour III, Mrs. W.F. Barclay, Wayne A. Barcomb, N.Carl Barefoot Jr.-Richmond Citizens' Fire Protection Committee, Russell Bargamin, Mrs. W.A. (Sara L.) Barger, John T. Barker, William H. Barker, John W. Barkley, Nella Barkley, Jon Barksdale
  - 1951-1967 Correspondence: Barn - Bas (Box-folder 3:2)
    Commander Barnes, Fred W. Barnes, Hamilton Barnes, R.G. Barnes Jr., Robert C. Barnes, W.P. Barnes-McGuire Clinic St. Luke's Hospital, Bill Barnett, Frank R. Barnett-National Strategy Information Center, Rose Barnett, Victor Barnett, Rev. William A. Barnett, William J. Baroody-American Enterprise Association, Ethel L. Barr, John C. Barr, John U. Barr, Mary M. Barr, Mrs. William A. Barr, E.C. Barrett III, Edward W. Barrett-Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism, George M. Barrett-Caesar Rodney High School, Dr. Joseph E. Barrett-Virginia Department of Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Allen Barringer, Victor C. Barringer, Karl W. Barron Sr., Michael Bennett Barrow, Carl Barry, Rey Barry, Harry Barsantee The Travelers, Alvy Bartholomew, Frances P. Bartlett- Facts in Education, Grady Bartlett, Violet Ainslie Bartlett, Mary S. Bartlette, Patricia Barton, Robert T. Barton Jr., Jack H. Baskerville-First and Merchants National Bank, Emmett E. Bass, Henry B. Bass-Oklahoma Civil War Centennial Commission, Spencer J. Bass M.D., Lewis Bassano
  - 1949-1966 Correspondence: Bat - Bay (Box-folder 3:3)
    John T. Bate, Sen. Fred W. Bateman, Stanley Bateman, Harold E. Bates, L. Bates, Robert Bates- The Meadville Tribune, Ernest A. Batkins, H. Barner Batte, L. Wayne Batty-Richmond Professional Institute-School of Music, Sen. John S. Battle, William C. Battle, Alvin J. Baum, Mrs. Alvin Baum, James J. Baumgartner, E.C. Baxendell, Camille Louise Baxter, Edith Oakley Baxter, James J.M. Baylor, George D. Baylor, Leon W. Baylor, Eugene M. Baynes
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence: Be - Bec (Box-folder 3:4)
    Edna McIntyre (Mrs. Haywood) Beach, Beadle Bumble Fund, Dennis M. Beagen, Mrs. R.E. Beal, Mrs. Fred H. (Ruby C.) Beale, Robert Beale Jr. N.E. Beall Jr., Mary J. Bean-District of Columbia Federation of Women's Clubs, Morris A. Bealle, William Roy Bean- St. Louis Hills News, James A. Bear Jr. -Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation, Margaret C. Beard, Sam Beard -WRAL-TV, Carolyn Beasley, Robert F. Beasley, A. Joynes Beattie, Josephine Powell Beaty, H.J. Beavers, Margery S. Beavers, R.L. Beavin, Jeannette Beazley, A.J. Beber, Arthur C. Beck- Richmond Forward, E.A. Beck-Henrico County Manager, Elizabeth C. Beck, Walter S. Beck, Albert L. Becker, B.V. Becker, Delores Beckman
  - 1956-1967 Correspondence: Bed - Bel (Box-folder 3:5)
    L.Wood Bedell-Central National Bank, Lucius Beebe, Sir Beef, Z.C. Begin, George Beiers-National Institute for Archaeology Education, William S. Beinecke-Sperry and Hutchinson, Edward Beirne Jr., Peter J. Beirne, Richard F. Beirne III- Covington Virginian, George Beiswanger Georgia State College for Women, Mrs. J.P. (Ida C.) Belcher, Ben Belchic - Winchester-Frederick County Civil War Centennial Commission, Winifred S. Beldon, Montgomery Belgion-Henry Regnery Company, Rev. J. Blanton Belk-St. Giles Presbyterian Church, Archie L. Bell, Mrs. B.M. Bell, C.E. Bell-Seaboard Airline Railroad Company, Francis Bell Jr., Hazel Bell, Sen. Heyward Bell, O.C. Bell - District of Columbia School Association, Rose W. Bell, Charles L. Bellew, Lewis Paul Bellin, P.N.L. Bellinger-Virginia Association of Electric Companies, Glenn A. Belson
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence: Bem - Bev (Box-folder 3:6)
    Sen. Fitzgerald Bemiss, Margaret Bemiss, S. Merrill Bemiss, Samuel M. Bemiss-Medical College of Virginia Foundation, Bertram Benedict, C.P. Benfield, R.V. Beninghove, Edward B. Benjamin, Elizabeth L. Bennett, Floyd S. Bennett, Hubert D. Bennett-Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia, J. Gordon Bennett, Thurman Bennett, William L. Bennett-International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, Fred W. Bennion-Wyoming Taxpayers Association, George A. Benson - The Toledo Times, Prof. Esor Ben-Sorek, Charles E. Bentley, S.W. Beretta, Alfred Bergdoll, James R. Bergdoll-Randolph-Macon College, Merton R. Berliner - Convention Subcommittee-Press Gallery-U.S. Congress, Francis L. Berkeley Jr.-Alderman Library, Russell Berkness, Ruth Berman, Jules E. Bernfeld, Barbara A. Bernhard-Delegation of the Commonwealth of Virginia, Hilliard Bernstein, Katherine Bernstein, L.E. Berry, Mary Berry, Sandra A. Berthene, Sidney L. Berz, Philip Bessom, John P. Bessor, Frank B. Best-WDIX, Charles S. Betts Jr. - American National Red Cross, Gail Betz, Marshall J. Beverly, W.W. Beverly-Atlantic Rural Exposition
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence - Bi (Box-folder 4:1)
    Edith Bibb, O.Y. Bibbs, Herbert E. Bickel-Virginia Malt Beverage Association-Virginia Transit Company, Thelma S. Biddle - Chesterfield County Public Schools, Walter J. Biddlecomb, Edward Bier-Office of the Chief Inspector, Ivan R. Bierly-William Volker Fund, Hudson Biery-Ohio Valley Improvement Association, Charles P. Bigger-Builders' Exchange Fund of Richmond, George Bijur, Sarah J.C. Billings, William D. Billings, Christopher Billopp (subject), Julien Binford-Mary Washington College, Binford Junior High School, Millard I. Binswanger, Birch Society, Sen. Lloyd C. Bird, Vivian Bird, Frank O. Birdsall-Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center, J.M. Birdsall-Federated Insurance, McLemore Birdsong - University of Virginia School of Medicine, Dave Birmingham, Birmingham Veteran's Day, Birth Control, Herman Bischoff, Walter Biscup- Tulsa Daily World, Edward Bishop, Howard W. Bishop-New York Circulation Manager's Association, L.W. Bishop-Virginia Industrial Development Corporation-Department of Conservation and Economic Development, Howard Bissell
  - 1955-1956 Correspondence: Jim Bishop (1907-1987) (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence: Blac - Blak (Box-folder 4:3)
    Byron Bacon Black, Creed C. Black- The Nashville Tennesseean and Chicago Daily News, Robert W. Black, Ronald Black- The Manchester Guardian, Russell Black, Shirley J. Black-Coast Federal Savings and Loan Association, Black-Eyed Pea Society of America, The Black Frog, Leonard A. Blackburn, H. Curtis Blackerby- Career Model Magazine, James Baylor Blackford, "Blackie", Mrs. Elliott Blackman, Charles B. Blackmar, J.V. Blackwell, William M. Blackwell, Robert Blaine Jr.-Dixie Readers' Service, Don Blair - Oklahoma State Medical Association, Morris M. Blair-University of Tulsa, Raymond N. Blair-Anglo-American School, Aldrich Blake - Focus Inc., E.G. Blake, Frorence Blakely-Duke University Library
  - 1957-1966 Correspondence: Blan - Bli (Box-folder 4:4)
    Robert E. Bland, Walter Blaney-Zaney Blaney Entertainment Unlimited, Helen R. Blankenship, Leonard M. Blankenship, Mrs. Roy T. Blankenship, Kermit A. Blanks-Virginia Transit Company, Robert M. Blanton, Betty Leigh (Mrs. Robert M.) Blanton, Charles A. Blanton II -Virginia State Bar Association, H.L. Blanton-Nottoway County Schools, Kelsey Blanton, R.E.D. Blanton, Mrs. Wyndham B. Blanton, John Blatchford- Modern Age, Betty Blaylock, A.G. Blazey M.D., S.B. Bledsoe, Thomas A. Bledsoe - Council for Basic Education, Edwin C. Bliss, Mason C. Bliss-Bliss Celebrity Bureau
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence: Blo - Bly (Box-folder 4:5)
    Charles J. Bloch, E. Wright Blodgett, Baron von Blomberg, M.L. Blonigan, Kay Blow, Charles Johnson Blue, Jay P. Blue, Ivy P. Blue Jr., Herman Blum, Andrew N. Blunt, Andrew W. Blunt, Julie C. Blunt, N.E. Blythe
  - 1951-1966 Correspondence: Bo - Bol (Box-folder 4:6)
    George Boardman Ph.D, Del. John B. Boatwright Jr.-Virginia Division of Statutory Research and Drafting, Michael Bennett Bobrow, Phil Bocke, Richard J. Bocklet, John H. Bocock, Walt Bodine-WDAF-TV Channel 4, Whit Bodkin, Norman M. Boehner, Carleton F. Boeke, Roderick H. Boes, Genevieve Boguess, Willis W. Bohannan, Hugo Bohl, Sid Boise, William Boisseau, Ben H. Bolen-State Commissioner of Parks, Mrs. Robert C. Boley, Prof. Bryan Bolich-Duke University School of Law, Judge A.J. Bolinger-Probate and Magistrate Court, C.L. Bolling-Associated Transport, Edward Bolling, Paul H. Bollinger-Controlled Manpower, Charles D. Bollman, Carl E. Bolte, Betty J. Bolton, Whitney Bolton
  - 1956-1967 Correspondence: Bon - Boo (Box-folder 4:7)
    Michael Jay Bonafield-Bunting and Associates Advertising, Fred Bonavita- Albuquerque Journal, James Roy Bond, Lawrence B. Bond-Catawba College, M. Louise Bondurant, Mary Bonham, Hal J. Bonney Jr.-Douglas MacAurthur Academy, Samuel E. Bonsack, The Book Mailer, Book Supplies, Carr E. Booker, Nancy H. Booker, R.E. Booker-Virginia State Bar, Col. Abbott Boone, Howard C. Boone, L. Roy Boone, C. Fitzpatrick Booth, Florence P. Booth, Lea Booth-Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges, Luther S. Booth, Wiliiam Edwin Booth-Camera Club of Richmond, Sen. Amistead L. Boothe
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence: Bor - Bow (Box-folder 5:1)
    Ed A. Borden, Arthur I. Boreman-Publisher, David S. Borland, George F. Borum- The Tidewater Review, Ralph Boryszewski-Association for Grand Jury Action, Blanche K and Lewis Hinton Bosher, Edgar I Bostwick-Travelers' Insurance Company, Robert I Boswell, A. Ware Bosworth-Bosworth Commission Company, Frederic M. Bosworth, Mrs. Raymond B. Bottom- The Daily Press, George A. Bottomley, Sara Frances Bottorf, Elizabeth Bouey-Yates, Thomas C. Boushall - Bank of Virginia, S. Miles Bouton, Rep. Frank T. Bow, William L. Bowden-University of Virginia Extension Division, Caroline Bowdler, Carroll G. Bowen-Oxford University Press, John R. Bower, Margaret F. Bowers-Virginia Society for the Prevention of Blindness, Thomas A. Bowers-Scituate Ambulance and Rescue Corps., Margaret Bowersett, Parker C. Bowery III, R.R. Bowker Company, Chester Bowles (subject), E.W. Bowles, George D. Bowles, L.J. Bowles, M.A. Bowles, Margaret H. Bowles, James C. Bowling-Philip Morris, Bowl[-?], Lester Inglis Bowman-Petersburg School Board, Earl E. Bowsman
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence: Boy - Bra (Box-folder 5:2)
    Dr. C.E. Boyd, Frank C. Boyd, Mrs. John W. Boyd, Mark F. Boyd, E.P. Boyden-Imperial County Welfare Department, Carl E. Boykin, John C. Boykin-University of Washington, Donzella Cross Boyle-Pro Patria Publications, Sarah Patton Boyle, Sam Boyte-The Conservative Club- Davidson College, Edward S. Boze Jr.-Virginia Steel Company, L. Brent Bozell, Thomas V. Braband-Mariners Museum, Lillian Brach, J.E. Bradford Jr.. Dr. M.E. Bradford-Northwestern State College of Louisiana and Hardin-Simmons University, Margaret L. Bradford, Elizabeth Bradley-American Association of Retired Persons, Robert M. Bradley, Booker T. Bradshaw, Elizabeth Bradshaw, Joseph R. Brady, R. Brady, William H. Brady Jr., F.O. Brafford, F.M. Bragg, Gloria Brahany, Col. William C. Braly, Jacques Bramhall-Morristown Forum Association, Max Brandel, Frederick R. Brandt, Karl E. Brandt, Brandy Rock Farm, Dr. Jerald A. Foster Brannon, Harvie Branscomb - Vanderbilt University, Mrs. (Mary C.) Clayton Brantly, Dr. Alton D. Brashear-Medical College of Virginia, G.H. Brauburger-Terminix Engineers, Brave New World, W.W. Brawley-People's Bank and Trust Company, Luther C. Brawner
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence - Bre (Box-folder 5:3)
    Donald L. Breed- The Journal-Standard, Edward L. Breeden Jr., Frances R. Breeden -Hope Inc., Bruce Alan Breitstein, Mrs. John A. Breneman, Mary Helen Brengel, James J. Brennan, Marjorie C. Brennan, Philip V. Brennan Jr.-Republican Policy Committee, Ruby G. Brennan, Andrew J. "Jack" Brent, Frank Bresinger, Irwin J. Breslauer-General Features Corporation, Harry H. Brewer-Wilson Paper Box Company, James H. Brewer-Virginia State College, Sen. Owen Brewster
  - 1956-1966 Correspondence - Bri (Box-folder 5:4)